Finding Aid for the Bion J. Arnold Reports on Operating Procedures of Suburban Railways in the Eastern United States LSC.0189
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bion J. Arnold reports on operating procedures of suburban railways in the Eastern United States
1908-1920
UCLA Library Special Collections
Arnold, Bion J. (Bion Joseph), 1861-1942
LSC.0189
2.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Bion J. Arnold was a consulting engineer on operating procedures of suburban railways in the Eastern United States. He founded The Arnold Company in Chicago, IL. This collection consists primarily of his consulting reports on railways, most prominently the Bay State Street Railway Company.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of collection unprocessed. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of receipt unknown.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303313606533
Biography/History
Bion J. Arnold was a consulting engineer on operating procedures of suburban railways in the Eastern United States. He founded The Arnold Company in Chicago, IL.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of reports written by Bion J. Arnold and his consulting company The Arnold Company about suburban railway operating procedures. A large portion of the reports are for the Bay State Street Railway Company.
- Correspondence and reports, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Notes, 1909-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Reports, 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Reports, c. 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Reports, c. 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Reports, 1908-1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Report: Detroit United Railway System, 1915 (Box 2)
- Reports: Louisville Railway Co., 1920 (Box 2)
- Report: Minneapolis Street Railway Company, 1916-1919 (Box 2)
- Report: Omaha Electric Light and Power Company, 1916 (Box 2)
- Report: New York State Railways, Rochester Lines, 1916 (Box 2)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, General and Miscellaneous Expenses, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, General Report on Operation, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Brockton Lines, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Chelsea Lines, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Fall River City Lines, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Haverhill Lines, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Hyde Park Lines, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Interurban Lines South of Boston, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Lawrence City Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Lowell City Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Lynn Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Nashua Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Quincy Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Reading and Woburn Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Salem Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Taunton Lines, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Summer Academy, Ipswich-Ipswich Junction, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Woburn-Malden route, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Montello-Bridgewater Route, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Lowell-Reading Route, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Malden-Revere Route, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Report: Bay State Street Railway Company, Rockland-Braintree Route, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 14)